<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Daily Tips</string>
    <string name="screen_title">30 Days of Self-Improvement</string>
    <string name="day_label">Day %d</string>

    <string name="tip_1_title">Set Goals</string>
    <string name="tip_1_short">Write three goals for the month and split them into steps.</string>
    <string name="tip_1_full">Define three key goals for this month and break each one into clear weekly actions.</string>
    <string name="tip_2_title">Morning Routine</string>
    <string name="tip_2_short">Take 10 calm minutes after waking up.</string>
    <string name="tip_2_full">Start the day with a simple routine: water, light movement, and a quiet start without your phone.</string>
    <string name="tip_3_title">Reading</string>
    <string name="tip_3_short">Read for at least 15-20 minutes.</string>
    <string name="tip_3_full">Spend 15-20 minutes reading a book or useful article to train focus and broaden your view.</string>
    <string name="tip_4_title">Walk</string>
    <string name="tip_4_short">Take a 20-minute walk outside.</string>
    <string name="tip_4_full">Go for a walk in fresh air to reset your mind, improve mood, and reduce screen fatigue.</string>
    <string name="tip_5_title">Gratitude</string>
    <string name="tip_5_short">Write three things you are grateful for today.</string>
    <string name="tip_5_full">In the evening, write three positive things from the day to shift focus toward progress and support.</string>
    <string name="tip_6_title">One Important Task</string>
    <string name="tip_6_short">Pick one key task and do it first.</string>
    <string name="tip_6_full">Choose the most important task and complete it early to guarantee progress even on a busy day.</string>
    <string name="tip_7_title">Digital Break</string>
    <string name="tip_7_short">Put away your phone and social media for 1-2 hours.</string>
    <string name="tip_7_full">Take a focused block without notifications and social feeds to restore attention.</string>
    <string name="tip_8_title">Water</string>
    <string name="tip_8_short">Drink at least 1.5 liters of water today.</string>
    <string name="tip_8_full">Keep a bottle nearby and drink water regularly to support energy and concentration.</string>
    <string name="tip_9_title">Early Wake-Up</string>
    <string name="tip_9_short">Wake up 30 minutes earlier than usual.</string>
    <string name="tip_9_full">Use extra morning time for planning, reading, or a calm breakfast before daily rush starts.</string>
    <string name="tip_10_title">No Multitasking</string>
    <string name="tip_10_short">Do only one task at a time for one hour.</string>
    <string name="tip_10_full">Single-task for one full hour to improve quality and finish work faster.</string>
    <string name="tip_11_title">Learning</string>
    <string name="tip_11_short">Watch a lesson or read a chapter on a new topic.</string>
    <string name="tip_11_full">Spend 20-30 minutes learning something new to build skills steadily.</string>
    <string name="tip_12_title">Tidy Space</string>
    <string name="tip_12_short">Clean one area: desk, shelf, or drawer.</string>
    <string name="tip_12_full">Organize one small zone around you to reduce chaos and feel more in control.</string>
    <string name="tip_13_title">Sleep</string>
    <string name="tip_13_short">Go to bed early enough to get at least 7 hours.</string>
    <string name="tip_13_full">Protect sleep time and reduce evening screen use to recover better.</string>
    <string name="tip_14_title">Reconnect</string>
    <string name="tip_14_short">Call or message someone you have not spoken to for a while.</string>
    <string name="tip_14_full">Reach out to a friend or relative to strengthen relationships and social support.</string>
    <string name="tip_15_title">Pause</string>
    <string name="tip_15_short">Take 5-10 minutes of complete rest without screens.</string>
    <string name="tip_15_full">Take a short pause where you do nothing productive to reset mental energy.</string>
    <string name="tip_16_title">Journaling</string>
    <string name="tip_16_short">Write down thoughts that worry or inspire you.</string>
    <string name="tip_16_full">Spend 10 minutes writing what is on your mind to reduce stress and clarify ideas.</string>
    <string name="tip_17_title">Compliment</string>
    <string name="tip_17_short">Give sincere praise or thanks to someone close.</string>
    <string name="tip_17_full">Express gratitude or appreciation to improve connection and positive mood.</string>
    <string name="tip_18_title">Say No</string>
    <string name="tip_18_short">Politely refuse one non-essential request.</string>
    <string name="tip_18_full">Protect your priorities by declining one unnecessary task today.</string>
    <string name="tip_19_title">Stretching</string>
    <string name="tip_19_short">Do 5-10 minutes of stretching or light exercise.</string>
    <string name="tip_19_full">Move your body for a few minutes to release tension and wake up physically.</string>
    <string name="tip_20_title">One Refusal</string>
    <string name="tip_20_short">Skip one harmful habit for today.</string>
    <string name="tip_20_full">Choose one small harmful habit and avoid it for one day to build self-control.</string>
    <string name="tip_21_title">Plan Tomorrow</string>
    <string name="tip_21_short">Write down three main tasks for tomorrow.</string>
    <string name="tip_21_full">Before sleep, define three priorities for tomorrow to start the day with clarity.</string>
    <string name="tip_22_title">Silence</string>
    <string name="tip_22_short">Spend 10 minutes in silence without devices.</string>
    <string name="tip_22_full">Take a quiet 10-minute break without music or phone to calm your thoughts.</string>
    <string name="tip_23_title">New Route</string>
    <string name="tip_23_short">Walk or travel using an unfamiliar route.</string>
    <string name="tip_23_full">Change your usual route to add novelty and break routine patterns.</string>
    <string name="tip_24_title">Help Someone</string>
    <string name="tip_24_short">Help someone without expecting gratitude.</string>
    <string name="tip_24_full">Do one useful action for another person to strengthen empathy and meaning.</string>
    <string name="tip_25_title">Weekly Review</string>
    <string name="tip_25_short">Write what worked and what to improve next week.</string>
    <string name="tip_25_full">Review your week in 10 minutes and decide one adjustment for the next week.</string>
    <string name="tip_26_title">Breathing</string>
    <string name="tip_26_short">Do 2-3 minutes of deep calm breathing.</string>
    <string name="tip_26_full">Slow breathing for a few minutes lowers stress and helps regain focus.</string>
    <string name="tip_27_title">One Question</string>
    <string name="tip_27_short">Ask yourself: what can I do better today than yesterday?</string>
    <string name="tip_27_full">Use this question to pick one small improvement in work, health, or communication.</string>
    <string name="tip_28_title">Limit Social Media</string>
    <string name="tip_28_short">Check social media only 2-3 times per day.</string>
    <string name="tip_28_full">Set fixed time windows for social apps to avoid endless scrolling.</string>
    <string name="tip_29_title">Praise Yourself</string>
    <string name="tip_29_short">Notice one achievement or effort from recent days.</string>
    <string name="tip_29_full">Acknowledge your progress to keep motivation stable and realistic.</string>
    <string name="tip_30_title">Plan Next Month</string>
    <string name="tip_30_short">Set 2-3 goals or habits for the next month.</string>
    <string name="tip_30_full">Summarize your 30-day progress and set a simple plan for the next month.</string>
</resources>
